Three of the Boys' Detective Agency have spent their summer vacation
&rlm;قضى 3 من "وكالة مباحث الصبية" عطلتهم
enthralled by a new video game.
&rlm;مأسورين بلعبة فيديو جديدة.
After talking to a fellow Teitan Grade School student
&rlm;بعد الحديث مع زميل طالب &rlm;بمدرسة "تيتان" الابتدائية
that we bumped into at a mini-mart,
&rlm;الذي التقينا به بالصدفة &rlm;بالسوق المركزي الصغير
we ended up going over to his relative's place to play the game.
&rlm;انتهينا بالذهاب لمنزل قريب للعب اللعبة.
I sensed something suspicious about the apartment.
&rlm;شعرت بشيء مريب بشأن الشقة.
But just then, Toshinari made a grisly discovery in the apartment next door.
&rlm;لكن بعد ذلك، قام "توشيناري" باكتشاف &rlm;مروع بالشقة المجاورة.
Elsewhere, there was another surprise between Detectives Satou and Takagi...
&rlm;في مكان آخر، كانت هناك مفاجأة أخرى &rlm;بين المحققين "ساتو" و"تاكاغي"...
I'm missing my you-know-what.
&rlm;فوت ما تعرفه.
Missed?! You don't mean–
&rlm;فات؟ لا تعنين...
It's embarrassing, so don't tell anyone, got it?
&rlm;الأمر محرج، لذا لا تخبر أحداً، مفهوم؟
-M-Miwako is having a baby? -What happy news!
&rlm;- سترزق "ميواكو" بطفل؟ &rlm;- يا له من خبر سعيد!
A chic and dashing detective show that holds up under the blazing sun!
&rlm;برنامج محققة أنيقة وذكية صامدة &rlm;تحت الشمس الحارقة!
Detective Takagi's gonna be a daddy?
&rlm;سيصبح المحقق "تاكاغي" والداً؟
A shocking trick that startles the two of them!
&rlm;خدعة صادمة تباغت كليهما!
Always determining the one truth with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
&rlm;يحدد الحقيقة الواحدة دائماً &rlm;بجسد طفل وعقل راشد.
his name is Detective Conan!
&rlm;اسمه هو المحقق "كونان"!
Metropolitan Police Detective Love Story (The Truth)
&rlm;"قصة حب محققة شرطة العاصمة (الحقيقة)"
Tokyo Metropolitan Police
&rlm;"شرطة العاصمة (طوكيو)"
Grumble
&rlm;"تذمر"
Grr...
&rlm;"تذ..."
I'm back!
&rlm;لقد عدت.
What's with this ominous vibe I'm getting?
&rlm;ما أمر هذا الشعور المشؤوم الذي أشعر به؟
Well, you see, Chiba...
&rlm;حسناً، كما ترى يا "شيبا"...
Okay, found it!
&rlm;حسناً، وجدتهما!
A bento lunch made on August 13th, and a newspaper from August 13th.
&rlm;علبة غداء معدة في 13 أغسطس &rlm;وصحيفة من 13 أغسطس.
Well, I do buy a newspaper every day.
&rlm;حسناً، أشتري صحيفة كل يوم.
Look, even if you're only taking care of him for a week,
&rlm;اسمع، حتى لو كنت تعتني به لأسبوع.
you can't feed a child nothing but snacks, mini-mart bento boxes and instant ramen.
&rlm;لا يمكنك إطعام طفل لا شيء سوى وجبات خفيفة &rlm;وعلب طعام السوق المركزي ومعكرونة فورية.
Shouldn't you give a little more thought to what he's eating?
&rlm;ألا يجب أن تفكر أكثر قليلاً فيما يأكله؟
You'll stunt his growth.
&rlm;ستعيق نموه.
S-Satou's maternal instincts are kicking in!
&rlm;بدأت غرائز أمومة "ساتو" تظهر.
And... And I'm the father!
&rlm;و...أنا الأب!
Hey, Takagi.
&rlm;"تاكاغي".
Did you go to the mini-mart and confirm his story?
&rlm;هل ذهبت للسوق المركزي الصغير &rlm;وتأكدت من القصة؟
Yes. The store's security camera caught everything.
&rlm;أجل، آلة تصوير أمن المتجر صورت كل شيء.
Around 6:00 PM yesterday, August 13th, Mr. Yasutomi was there shopping.
&rlm;حوالي 6:00 مساء أمس، 13 أغسطس، &rlm;كان السيد "ياسوتومي" يتسوق هناك.
It also showed Toshinari and Noriya there at the same time.
&rlm;أظهرت أيضاً أن "توشيناري" و"نوريا" &rlm;كانا هناك بنفس الوقت.
Oh, and there was apparently an accident six months ago
&rlm;وكان هناك على ما يبدو حادث منذ 6 أشهر
in front of the florist's next door to the mini-mart.
&rlm;أمام متجر الزهور بجوار السوق &rlm;المركزي الصغير.
-An accident? -Yes.
&rlm;- حادث؟ &rlm;- أجل.
Apparently, a woman ran into the street.
&rlm;على ما يبدو، ركضت امرأة بالشارع.
The driver swerved to avoid her, but it was too late.
&rlm;انحرف السائق لتجنبها &rlm;لكن كان الأوان قد فات.
After he hit her,
&rlm;بعد أن صدمها.
he slammed into the guard rail in the oncoming lane and lost consciousness.
&rlm;اصطدم بقوة بحاجز الطريق القادم &rlm;بالاتجاه العكسي وفقد وعيه.
A bystander called an ambulance, and that saved the driver's life,
&rlm;اتصل أحد المارة بسيارة إسعاف، &rlm;وهذا أنقذ حياة السائق.
but his car had snagged the woman's clothes,
&rlm;لكن ملابس المرأة علقت بسيارته.
and no one noticed her underneath the car.
&rlm;ولم يلحظها أحد تحت السيارة.
They say the delay in treatment cost her her life.
&rlm;يقولون إن التأخير بالعلاج كلفها حياتها.
The driver's statement said that it looked like she ran into the street
&rlm;أشارت إفادة السائق أنها بدت كأنها &rlm;ركضت للشارع.
because she was being chased by someone.
&rlm;لأن شخصاً ما يطاردها.
So? What does that have to do with this murder?
&rlm;إذن؟ ما علاقة هذا بجريمة القتل هذه؟
The thing is, the mini-mart cashier apparently saw the whole thing.
&rlm;الأمر هو، يبدو أن أمين صندوق السوق &rlm;المركزي الصغير رأى كل شيء.
He saw Mr. Yasutomi running from the scene.
&rlm;رأى السيد "ياسوتومي" &rlm;يركض من مكان الحادث.
And as for the woman who was run over, she–
&rlm;وبالنسبة للمرأة التي دهست، هي...
Yes.
&rlm;أجل.
It was my sister, Mika, who died in that accident.
&rlm;كانت أختي "ميكا"، التي ماتت بهذا الحادث.
Ever since then, I've made a point of laying flowers at the scene every day.
&rlm;منذ ذلك الحين، حرصت على وضع &rlm;الزهور بمكان الحادث كل يوم.
O-Oh, is that right?
&rlm;حقاً؟
That flower seems like a bit of a gaudy choice to set out, though...
&rlm;هذه الزهرة تبدو خياراً مبهرجاً &rlm;لاختياره رغم هذا...
My sister loved pink, so I thought it would be nice
&rlm;كانت أختي تحب اللون الوردي، &rlm;لذا فكرت أنه سيكون لطيفاً
to set out flowers like that every once in a while.
&rlm;أن أضع زهوراً كهذه من حين لآخر.
Ah, I see.
&rlm;فهمت.
Say, mister...
&rlm;قل لي يا سيد...
Was your sister having any problems?
&rlm;هل كانت أختك تواجه أي مشاكل؟
For instance...
&rlm;على سبيل المثال...
A stalker or something, maybe?
&rlm;شخص يلاحقها أو شيء ربما؟
-Was there one? -No.
&rlm;- هل كان هناك مترصد؟ &rlm;- كلا.
She never mentioned anything about that to me.
&rlm;لم تذكر لي شيئاً عن هذا.
I knew it. The man who killed Mr. Yasutomi...
&rlm;كنت متأكداً. الرجل الذي قتل &rlm;السيد "ياسوتومي"...
...was this man. Toshinari Shiga.
&rlm;...كان هذا الرجل، "توشيناري شيغا".
But he has an alibi.
&rlm;لكن لديه حجة غياب.
For the two hours between 7:00 and 9:00 on August 13th, the time of the murder,
&rlm;بالساعتين بين 7:00 و9:00 بـ13 أغسطس، &rlm;وقت وقوع الجريمة.
he was with Noriya the entire time.
&rlm;كان مع "نوريا" طوال الوقت.
I'm going to let some fresh air in.
&rlm;سأدخل بعض من الهواء النقي.
No way! The sun is going down already! I have to get home!
&rlm;مستحيل! الشمس تغرب بالفعل! &rlm;يجب أن أعود للمنزل.
Seriously? I just opened this big of chips!
&rlm;جدياً؟ فتحت كيس رقائق البطاطا المقلية &rlm;الكبير هذا.
Genta, you're getting them everywhere!
&rlm;"جنتا"، تجلبهم بكل مكان!
Do you have a bowl or something?
&rlm;هل لديك وعاء أو شيء؟
I think he has paper ones.
&rlm;أعتقد أن لديه أوعية ورقية.
What happened to your leg?
&rlm;ماذا حدث لساقك؟
It looks like bruises from pinching.
&rlm;تبدو ككدمات من القرص.
I guess I was bitten by mosquitoes and scratched too hard.
&rlm;أعتقد أن البعوض قرصني وحككت بها بشدة.
Hey, about that Yaiba movie you watched last night, was it...
&rlm;مهلاً، ماذا عن فيلم "يابا" الذي &rlm;شاهدته الليلة الماضية، كان...
Yeah, that's right. I held it in so long I thought I was going to burst.
&rlm;أجل، هذا صحيح. تماسكت فترة طويلة &rlm;لدرجة أنني ظننت أنني سأنفجر.
That means that that newspaper is...
&rlm;هذا يعني أن تلك الصحيفة هي...
It can't be.
&rlm;مستحيل.
Conan?
&rlm;"كونان"؟
Just as I thought!
&rlm;كما ظننت بالضبط!
The only one missing is from August 12th.
&rlm;الوحيدة المفقودة هي من 12 أغسطس.
No doubt about it...
&rlm;لا شك بالأمر...
This man is the killer.
&rlm;هذا الرجل هو القاتل.
He manipulated the passage of time to give himself an alibi.
&rlm;تلاعب بمرور الوقت لإعطاء نفسه حجة غياب.
He even manipulated Noriya's feelings.
&rlm;حتى أنه تلاعب بمشاعر "نوريا".
At any rate, if Toshinari and Noriya were next door to the crime scene
&rlm;بأي حال، إن كان "توشيناري" و"نوريا" &rlm;بالشقة المجاورة لمسرح الجريمة.
from 7:00 to 9:00 PM last night, the window the murder was committed in,
&rlm;من 7:00 حتى 9:00 الليلة الماضية، &rlm;الوقت الذي وقعت به الجريمة.
but didn't hear any strange sounds because of the movie they were watching,
&rlm;لكن لم يسمعا أي أصوات غريبة &rlm;بسبب الفيلم الذي كانا يشاهدانه.
our only choice is to question the other residents of the building.
&rlm;خيارنا الوحيد هو سؤال &rlm;سكان المبنى الآخرين.
This building is scheduled to be demolished next year, though.
&rlm;من المقرر أن يتم هدم هذا المبنى &rlm;العام المقبل رغم هذا.
The only other residents are an old couple on the second floor.
&rlm;الساكنان الآخران الوحيدان هما &rlm;زوجان عجوزان بالطابق الثاني.
They say they spent last night at their grandchildren's.
&rlm;قالا إنهما قضيا الليلة الماضية &rlm;بمنزل أحفادهما.
Really?
&rlm;حقاً؟
-Haibara, get rid of the others. -Sure.
&rlm;- "هايبارا"، تخلصي من الآخرين. &rlm;- حسناً.
Come on, everyone. Let's have a sleepover at the Doctor's place and game all night!
&rlm;هيا جميعاً، دعونا نقضي الليلة بمنزل &rlm;الطبيب ونلعب طوال الليل!
Let's play Titan Hunter, then!
&rlm;- لنلعب "صياد العمالقة" إذن! &rlm;- فكرة جيدة!
I'll go grab the disc from my house, then!
&rlm;سأذهب لجلب القرص من منزلي إذن!
Care to join us, Noriya? We'll want to pick your brain over the game.
&rlm;هل تود أن تنضم لنا يا "نوريا"؟ &rlm;سنحتاج نصيحتك بشأن اللعبة.
Besides, you don't want to sleep next to a murder scene, do you?
&rlm;بالإضافة لذلك، لا تريد أن تنام بجوار &rlm;مسرح جريمة، أليس كذلك؟
You're not going?
&rlm;ألن تذهب؟
I will. But first...
&rlm;سأفعل لكن أولاً...
Why would you move into a building that's going to be demolished next year?
&rlm;لم تنتقل لمبنى سيهدم العام المقبل؟
I wanted to distract myself with a change of scenery.
&rlm;أردت أن أشتت انتباهي بتغيير الإطلالة.
I used to live with my sister, and she died in that accident...
&rlm;كنت أعيش مع أختي وماتت بهذا الحادث...
But you moved in a month ago, right?
&rlm;لكنك انتقلت منذ شهر، صحيح؟
You'd think that you would have bought at least a pot or a skillet.
&rlm;لفكرت في شراء قدر أو مقلاة على الأقل.
But there's nothing here at all.
&rlm;لكن لا يوجد شيء هنا مطلقاً.
I'm a terrible cook, so I never bothered to get any cooking utensils.
&rlm;أنا طاه مروع، لذا لم أكلف نفسي قط &rlm;عناء شراء أي أواني طهي.
But there isn't any detergent or a sponge or scrub brush by the sink.
&rlm;لكن لا يوجد أي منظفات أو إسفنجة &rlm;أو فرشاة تنظيف بجانب المغسلة.
Doesn't that mean that you also don't have any dishes or glasses?
&rlm;ألا يعني هذا أنه ليس لديك &rlm;أي أطباق أو أكواب أيضاً؟
Yes. I'd planned to get some soon.
&rlm;أجل. خططت لشراء بعض منهم قريباً.
Oh, really? I assumed it was because you planned to move out
&rlm;حقاً؟ افترضت أنك لم تفعل لأنك &rlm;خططت للانتقال من الشقة.
just as soon as you had murdered your neighbor, Mr. Yasutomi.
&rlm;ما أن تقتل جارك السيد "ياسوتومي".
What are you talking about, Conan?
&rlm;ما الذي تتحدث عنه يا "كونان"؟
Toshinari was watching TV during the crime window,
&rlm;كان "توشيناري" يشاهد التلفاز &rlm;خلال وقت وقوع الجريمة
from 7:00 to 9:00 last night.
&rlm;من 7:00 حتى 9:00 الليلة الماضية.
Noriya was with him.
&rlm;كان "نوريا" معه.
Didn't you hear Noriya?
&rlm;ألم تسمعي "نوريا"؟
He said he held it in as he watched the whole movie.
&rlm;قال إنه تماسك بينما كان يشاهد كل الفيلم.
Doesn't that suggest that there were no commercials for the whole two hours?
&rlm;ألا يشير هذا لعدم وجود إعلانات &rlm;لساعتين كاملتين؟
Oh, right! A rental DVD!
&rlm;صحيح! قرص فيديو رقمي مستأجر!
Rental DVD?
&rlm;قرص فيديو رقمي مستأجر؟
Yes, if it's being aired on TV,
&rlm;أجل، إن كان يعرض على التلفاز.
then the movie's also available for rent now.
&rlm;إذن الفيلم متاح أيضاً للاستئجار الآن.
It should also be available for purchase.
&rlm;ينبغي أن يكون متاحاً للشراء أيضاً.
I follow you. If he bought the DVD and put it in the player ahead of time,
&rlm;أفهمك، إن اشترى القرص الرقمي ووضعه &rlm;بالمشغل قبل الوقت المحدد.
and then hit Play at exactly the right time,
&rlm;ثم قام بتشغيله بالوقت المحدد بالضبط.
it would look to a child like it was airing on TV.
&rlm;فسيبدو لطفل أنه يعرض بالتلفاز.
But Toshinari...
&rlm;لكن "توشيناري"...
Didn't you say that on the 13th, the night of the murder,
&rlm;ألم تقل أن في يوم 13، ليلة وقوع الجريمة.
you played that game with Noriya in addition to watching the movie with him?
&rlm;لعبت تلك اللعبة مع "نوريا" بالإضافة &rlm;لمشاهدة الفيلم معه؟
Yes. Both before and after the movie.
&rlm;أجل، قبل وبعد الفيلم.
He couldn't have committed it, then.
&rlm;لا يمكنه أن يكون ارتكبها إذن.
Was that really the 13th?
&rlm;هل كان هذا حقاً يوم 13؟
Yes,
&rlm;أجل.
he said he had Noriya check the date on that paper they bought at the mini-mart.
&rlm;قال إنه جعل "نوريا" يتحقق من التاريخ &rlm;بهذه الصحيفة التي اشترياها بالمتجر.
Isn't that right?
&rlm;أليس هذا صحيحاً؟
-Yes. -See?
&rlm;- أجل. &rlm;- أترى؟
That day was definitely August 13th.
&rlm;كان ذلك اليوم 13 أغسطس بالتأكيد.
Oh, I see. I had it all wrong?
&rlm;فهمت. هل أسأت الفهم تماماً؟
Mini-marts don't sell papers from a day in the future, now do they?
&rlm;لا تبيع الأسواق المركزية الصغيرة &rlm;صحف اليوم التالي، أليس كذلك؟
Tabloids!
&rlm;صحف الفضائح!
Those so-called "evening edition" papers
&rlm;تلك التي تسمى صحف "الطبعة المسائية" .
have the next day's date printed on them!
&rlm;تطبع عليها تاريخ اليوم التالي!
If he bought that and had Noriya check the date for him,
&rlm;إن اشتراها وجعل "نوريا" &rlm;يتحقق من التاريخ له.
he could make him think that it was a different day.
&rlm;فيمكن أن يجعله يظن أنه كان يوماً مختلفاً.
Now that you mention it, August 12th was the only day there's no paper for.
&rlm;بعد أن ذكرت الأمر، 12 أغسطس كان اليوم &rlm;الوحيد الذي لم يكن له صحيفة.
I get it.
&rlm;فهمت.
He got rid of the paper dated the 13th that he bought on the 12th.
&rlm;تخلص من الصحيفة المؤرخة بيوم 13 &rlm;التي اشتراها يوم 12.
In other words, it was actually the night of August 12th
&rlm;بكلمات أخرى، كانت ليلة 12 أغسطس بالفعل.
that you watched that movie with Noriya,
&rlm;التي شاهدت بها هذا الفيلم مع "نوريا".
giving you ample opportunity to commit the murder on the night of the 13th.
&rlm;مما يتيح لك فرصة كبيرة لارتكاب &rlm;جريمة القتل بليلة يوم 13.
N-Now wait just a minute!
&rlm;انتظروا لحظة!
Didn't you hear Noriya? He said that we watched the movie yesterday!
&rlm;ألم تسمعوا "نوريا"؟ &rlm;قال إننا شاهدنا الفيلم أمس!
Even a child can tell the difference between yesterday and two days ago!
&rlm;حتى الطفل يمكنه معرفة الفرق &rlm;بين الأمس وقبل يومين!
If you think I'm lying, call Noriya back here and ask him!
&rlm;إن كنتم تظنون أنني أكذب، &rlm;سأستدعي "نوريا" إلى هنا وأسأله!
He knows that today is the day after we saw that movie!
&rlm;يعلم أن اليوم هو اليوم التالي &rlm;لمشاهدتنا للفيلم!
Actually, Noriya said something about that, too.
&rlm;في الواقع، قال "نوريا" شيئاً &rlm;عن هذا أيضاً.
On the evening of August 13th, after you came back from the store,
&rlm;بليلة 13 أغسطس، بعد عودتكما من المتجر.
he played that game until the movie started.
&rlm;لعب تلك اللعبة حتى بدأ الفيلم.
And after it ended, he went back to playing it until late at night.
&rlm;وبعد انتهائه، عاد للعبها &rlm;حتى وقت متأخر بالليل.
He then got up early, and after playing the game some more,
&rlm;ثم استيقظ مبكراً وبعد اللعب مجدداً.
Noriya went to the store with you to buy breakfast around 6:00 AM.
&rlm;ذهب "نوريا" للمتجر معك لشراء الإفطار &rlm;حوالي الساعة الـ6:00 صباحاً.
After playing the game again until lunch, he took a nap.
&rlm;بعد أن لعب مجدداً حتى الغداء، &rlm;نام القيلولة.
He then got up and played the game some more.
&rlm;ثم استيقظ ولعب مجدداً.
He was hungry by then, so you two went to the store earlier and ran into us.
&rlm;كان جائعاً بذلك الوقت، لذا ذهبتما &rlm;للمتجر بوقت سابق والتقيتما بنا.
And he said he was with me the entire time he was playing the game, remember?
&rlm;وقال إنه كان معي طوال وقت &rlm;لعبه للعبة، هل تتذكر؟
Yes. But he also said that you went out for a bit
&rlm;أجل، لكنه قال أيضاً إنك خرجت قليلاً.
after you went to the store and ate breakfast.
&rlm;بعد ذهابكما للمتجر وتناول الإفطار.
You told him to wear headphones while you were gone.
&rlm;أخبرته أن يضع سماعات الرأس &rlm;بينما أنت بالخارج.
You went out. Where?
&rlm;خرجت؟ أين؟
I-I just stepped out for a smoke.
&rlm;خرجت لأدخن سيجارة.
Besides, that was this morning.
&rlm;بالإضافة، كان ذلك هذا الصباح.
Timing-wise, it has nothing to do with the murder.
&rlm;فيما يتعلق بالتوقيت، لا علاقة له &rlm;بجريمة القتل.
Speaking of time,
&rlm;بالحديث عن الوقت.
there isn't a single clock in this whole apartment, is there?
&rlm;لا يوجد ساعة واحدة بكل الشقة، &rlm;أليس كذلك؟
The only person who knows what time it is is you, with your watch.
&rlm;الشخص الوحيد الذي يعرف الوقت &rlm;هو أنت، بساعة يدك.
Plus, there are these heavy curtains on all the windows.
&rlm;بالإضافة، هناك تلك الستائر الثقيلة &rlm;على كل النوافذ.
And if you're eating snacks the whole time you're gaming,
&rlm;وإن كنت تتناول وجبات خفيفة &rlm;طوال الوقت الذي تلعب به.
you won't get hungry, either.
&rlm;فلن تشعر بالجوع أيضاً.
That would make it really easy to lose track of time, now wouldn't it?
&rlm;هذا يجعل من السهل جداً فقدان &rlm;الإحساس بالوقت، أليس كذلك؟
I really think you should buy a clock.
&rlm;أعتقد أنك يجب أن تشتري ساعة حقاً.
S-Sure...
&rlm;بالتأكيد...
Oh, I see. So this is how it went down:
&rlm;فهمت، إذن إليك ما حدث.
On the 12th, the day before the murder, you bought an evening edition at the store
&rlm;يوم 12، اليوم السابق لجريمة القتل، &rlm;اشتريت طبعة مسائية من المتجر.
and made Noriya think that it was actually the 13th.
&rlm;وجعلت "نوريا" يعتقد أنه كان يوم 13.
That night, you let him play his game until after 10:00 or so
&rlm;تلك الليلة، تركته يلعب لعبته &rlm;لحوالي الساعة الـ10:00
and then told him it was time for the movie.
&rlm;ثم قلت له إنه حان وقت الفيلم.
Then, assuming you let him play until early morning after having him
&rlm;ثم، على افتراض أنك تركته يلعب حتى &rlm;الصباح الباكر، بعد أن جعلته.
watch the movie on DVD until about midnight,
&rlm;يشاهد الفيلم على فيديو رقمي &rlm;حتى منتصف الليل تقريباً.
it was really the afternoon of the 13th
&rlm;كان حقاً بعد ظهر يوم 13
when you woke him up and said it was morning.
&rlm;حين أيقظته وقلت إنه الصباح.
You let him play until evening, and when you said "Let's buy breakfast"
&rlm;تركته يلعب حتى المساء وحين قلت &rlm;"دعنا نشتري الإفطار".
and went to the store, that was actually 6:00 PM on the 13th.
&rlm;وذهبتما للمتجر، كانت الساعة &rlm;الـ6:00 مساء يوم 13 في الواقع.
Oh, I get it! The sun is out at both 6:00 AM and 6:00 PM this time of year!
&rlm;فهمت! لا يوجد شمس الساعة الـ6:00 صباحاً &rlm;والـ6:00 مساءً بهذا الوقت من العام
And then, when you stepped out to run an errand after "breakfast,"
&rlm;وبعد ذلك، حين خرجت للقيام &rlm;بمهمة بعد "الإفطار".
you had plenty of time to murder Mr. Yasutomi.
&rlm;كان لديك متسع من الوقت &rlm;لقتل السيد "ياسوتومي".
Noriya was wearing headphones then, so he wouldn't have heard a thing.
&rlm;كان "نوريا" يضع سماعات الرأس حينها، &rlm;لذا لم يسمع شيئاً.
Afterwards, you came back to your apartment
&rlm;بعد ذلك، عدت لشقتك.
and had Noriya keep playing until early morning.
&rlm;وجعلت "نوريا" يستمر باللعب &rlm;حتى الصباح الباكر.
If you told him to take a nap and let him sleep until noon today, the 14th,
&rlm;إن أخبرته أن ينام القيلولة &rlm;وتركته ينام حتى ظهر اليوم 14.
it would have seemed to Noriya that the 13th and 14th were only one day.
&rlm;لبدا لـ"نوريا" أن يوم 13 و14 &rlm;كانا يوماً واحداً.
Well? Did I get anything wrong?
&rlm;حسناً؟ هل أخطأت في شيء؟ &rlm;كيف تتوقعان مني الإجابة على هذا؟
What possible motive would I have?
&rlm;ما هو الدافع المحتمل لدي؟
Your sister sure is pretty!
&rlm;شقيقتك جميلة بالتأكيد!
Hey! Kid!
&rlm;مهلاً أيها الصبي!
It's strange. She isn't looking into the camera in any of these at the end.
&rlm;الأمر غريب. إنها لا تنظر لآلة التصوير &rlm;بأي من هذه بالنهاية.
And there's some kinda hole at the tops.
&rlm;وهناك نوع من الثقوب بالقمم.
You sure must love your sister!
&rlm;لابد أنك أحببت أختك بالتأكيد.
I bet you had a bunch of pictures of your sister pinned up somewhere
&rlm;أراهن أنه كان لديك مجموعة صور &rlm;لأختك معلقة بمكان ما.
that you'd taken without her knowing!
&rlm;التقطتها بدون معرفتها!
-Are those from– -The stalker?!
&rlm;- هل هذه من... &rlm;- المترصد؟
Come to think of it, Forensics mentioned something about that.
&rlm;بعد التفكير بالأمر، ذكر الطب الشرعي &rlm;شيئاً عن هذا.
There was a cork board in Mr. Yasutomi's room with lots of photos pinned to it,
&rlm;كان هناك لوح فلين بغرفة السيد "ياسوتومي" &rlm;معلق عليه الكثير من الصور.
but they didn't line up with the sun-bleached areas on the board.
&rlm;لكنها لم تصطف مع المناطق الباهتة &rlm;من الشمس على اللوح.
So these are the pictures that were really pinned up there.
&rlm;لذا هذه هي الصور التي كانت &rlm;معلقة عليه حقاً.
After the murder, you took them down to remove any connection to you,
&rlm;بعد جريمة القتل، أزلتهم &rlm;لاستبعاد أي علاقة بك.
and you replaced them with pictures you found in Yasutomi's apartment, right?
&rlm;واستبدلتهم بصور وجدتها في شقة &rlm;"ياسوتومي"، أليس كذلك؟
If that's the case, the camera files these were made from
&rlm;إن كان هذا صحيحاً، ملفات آلة التصوير &rlm;التي طبعت منها هذه الصور
might still be on the laptop that was on Yasutomi's desk.
&rlm;قد لا تزال باقية على الحاسوب المحمول &rlm;الذي كان على مكتب "ياسوتومي".
Check it out right away. They're probably already deleted, though.
&rlm;تفقدها على الفور. &rlm;حذفت بالفعل غالباً رغم هذا.
On it!
&rlm;لك هذا!
I think they're still there.
&rlm;أعتقد أنها لا تزال موجودة.
I didn't think that far ahead.
&rlm;لم أفكر لهذا الحد.
Anyway, the only reason I took her pictures down
&rlm;على أي حال، السبب الوحيد &rlm;الذي جعلني أزيل صورها.
was because I didn't want them hanging in that stalker bastard's apartment.
&rlm;كان لأنني لم أردهم معلقين &rlm;بشقة هذا المترصد اللعين.
Then Mr. Yasutomi really was stalking your sister?
&rlm;إذن كان السيد "ياسوتومي" &rlm;يلاحق أختك حقاً؟
Yes. I found out two months ago.
&rlm;أجل. اكتشفت منذ شهرين.
I was placing flowers at the spot she died like I always do,
&rlm;كنت أضع زهوراً بالمكان الذي ماتت به &rlm;كما أفعل دائماً.
and he came up to me.
&rlm;وجاء لي.
He asked me if I was also a "fan."
&rlm;سألني إن كنت "معجباً" أيضاً.
I was curious, so I followed him. That's when I saw it through the window.
&rlm;شعرت بالفضول، لذا تبعته. &rlm;حينها رأيتهم من خلال النافذة.
Dozens of her pictures were pinned up,
&rlm;كان هناك العشرات من صورها معلقة.
and he was muttering that it was her fault for running away.
&rlm;وكان يدمدم أنه كان خطأها أنها هربت.
Hang on, that report that it looked like she was being chased
&rlm;انتظر، حين ذكر في التقرير أنها كانت &rlm;تبدو كأن شخصاً يطاردها.
when she ran into the street, that was...
&rlm;حين ركضت بالشارع، كان هذا...
Yes. She ran into the street when she was being chased by him
&rlm;أجل. ركضت بالشارع حين كان يطاردها.
and she was hit by that car.
&rlm;وصدمتها تلك السيارة.
I know because I got him to confess before I killed him.
&rlm;أعلم لأنني جعلته يعترف قبل أن أقتله.
"Why did you run away," I asked!
&rlm;سألته لم هرب.
"Why didn't you tell the EMTs that my sister was under the car?!"
&rlm;لماذا لم يخبر المسعفين أن أختي &rlm;تحت السيارة؟
If he'd said something, she might still be alive!
&rlm;إن قال شيئاً، لكانت لا تزال حية!
He said... He said it was because he was scared!
&rlm;قال...لأنه كان خائفاً!
And so you moved next to Mr. Yasutomi and put your plan into motion?
&rlm;فانتقلت بجانب السيد "ياسوتومي" &rlm;وبدأت بتنفيذ خطتك؟
Yes, I was asked a while ago to look after Noriya for a week.
&rlm;أجل، طلب مني منذ فترة &rlm;أن أعتني بـ"نوريا" لأسبوع.
I never expected that I would be able to fool him so easily, though.
&rlm;لم أتوقع قط أن أخدعه &rlm;بهذه السهولة رغم هذا.
What are you talking about?
&rlm;ما الذي تتحدث عنه؟
It "worked" because Noriya pinched his own leg
&rlm;نجحت الخطة لأن "نوريا" قرص ساقه
to stay awake and play that game for so long.
&rlm;ليظل مستيقظاً ويلعب تلك اللعبة &rlm;لوقت طويل.
Because he'd been asked by his mother to stay with you and cheer you up.
&rlm;لأن والدته طلبت منه أن يظل معك ويروح عنك.
This crazy plan of yours never would have worked otherwise.
&rlm;لن تنجح خطتك المجنونة تلك أبداً دون ذلك.
Now I get it...
&rlm;فهمت الآن...
He was the one who was looking after me.
&rlm;كان هو من يعتني بي.
So, what's going to happen with Noriya?
&rlm;إذن ما الذي سيحدث لـ"نوريا"؟
Until his mother comes back, he's going to stay at Dr. Agasa's house.
&rlm;حتى تعود والدته، سيظل &rlm;بمنزل الطبيب "أغازا".
Apparently, his mother called him and told him
&rlm;على ما يبدو اتصلت به والدته وأخبرته.
that Toshinari had to go on a trip for a while.
&rlm;أن "توشيناري" اضطر أن يذهب &rlm;في رحلة لبعض من الوقت.
Oh?
&rlm;إذن هل ستخبرني؟
To you, obviously!
&rlm;لك بالتأكيد!
It was going to be a surprise!
&rlm;كانت ستكون مفاجأة!
I was going to give you the false dragonheads along with the ring!
&rlm;كنت سأعطيك الزهور مع الخاتم.
Flowers and a ring?
&rlm;زهور وخاتم؟
Instead of all that, give me your red lapel pin instead.
&rlm;بدلاً من كل هذا، أعطني دبوس &rlm;طية السترة الأحمر.
Red pin?
&rlm;دبوس أحمر؟
The ones given out to members of Criminal Investigations Division?
&rlm;الذي يعطونه لأفراد قسم &rlm;التحقيقات الجنائية؟
Why would you want mine?
&rlm;لم تريدين دبوسي؟
You said you were going to do right by me, didn't you?
&rlm;قلت إنك ستعاملني معاملة جيدة، أليس كذلك؟
For the love of... I tackled that suspect you had cuffed
&rlm;بالله...أمسكت هذا المشتبه به الذي قيدته.
when he almost got away from you, remember?
&rlm;حين أوشك على الهرب منك، أتتذكر؟ &rlm;لابد أن التصادم أوقع دبوسي.
I noticed it was missing afterwards and went back and searched everywhere,
&rlm;لاحظت أنني فقدته بعد ذلك &rlm;وعدت وبحثت بكل مكان.
but I couldn't find it!
&rlm;لكن لم أستطع العثور عليه!
Oh, I picked that up and put it in my left pants pocket.
&rlm;التقطته ووضعته بالجيب الأيسر بسروالي.
-Sorry, I should have told you! -No way!
&rlm;- آسف، كان يجب أن أخبرك. &rlm;- مستحيل!
Seriously?!
&rlm;جدياً؟
-Hey! Satou! -Got it!
&rlm;- مهلاً! "ساتو"! &rlm;- وجدته!
My red pin! What a relief!
&rlm;دبوسي الأحمر. &rlm;يا لها من راحة!
Everyone wears them, but it's not like it's mandatory.
&rlm;يضعه الجميع، لكنه ليس إلزامياً.
If you'd gone to the bosses, I'm sure they would have given you a new one.
&rlm;إن كنت ذهبت للرؤساء، لأعطوك &rlm;دبوساً جديداً بالتأكيد.
Oh, really?
&rlm;حقاً؟
I assumed I'd have to file an apology, so I was too embarrassed to bring it up.
&rlm;افترضت أنني يجب أن أقدم اعتذاراً، &rlm;لذا كنت محرجة بشدة من ذكر الأمر.
Boy, I've been a moody wreck ever since!
&rlm;يا للهول! كان مزاجي متعكراً من ذلك الوقت.
Uh... When you said you were missing something earlier, you meant–
&rlm;حين قلت إنك فقدت شيئاً بوقت سابق، &rlm;كنت تعنين...
Yep! This red pin!
&rlm;أجل، هذا الدبوس الأحمر.
Look out! Watch it!
&rlm;احذر! انتبه!
Hey, what are you moping about?
&rlm;مهلاً، ما سبب كآبتك؟
We nabbed the culprit in no time flat, so let's see some spring in your step!
&rlm;أمسكنا المتهم بسرعة، &rlm;لذا اظهر بعض من السعادة.
Yeah...
&rlm;أجل...
Is it just me, or is everybody...
&rlm;هل أتخيل أم الجميع...
They're looking at us, aren't they?
&rlm;ينظر إلينا الجميع، أليس كذلك؟
Miwako!
&rlm;"ميواكو"!
Yumi? And Chiba?
&rlm;"يومي"؟ و"شيبا"؟
Hey, Yumi... Everybody's staring at us.
&rlm;"يومي"...الجميع يحدق بنا.
You know better than anyone.
&rlm;تعرفين أكثر من أي شخص.
Miwako, I hear you missed a little something?
&rlm;"ميواكو"، هل فوت شيئاً صغيراً؟
Oh, that! Don't worry, I found it!
&rlm;هذا! لا تقلقي، وجدته!
-Found it?
&rlm;- وجدته؟
Look, Takagi said he found it for me.
&rlm;انظري، قال "تاكاغي" إنه وجده لي.
If he'd told me earlier, I wouldn't have been in the dumps this whole time.
&rlm;إن أخبرني بوقت سابق، &rlm;لما تعكر مزاجي كل هذا الوقت.
D-Do they think that she's...
&rlm;هل يعتقدون أنها...
Huh? Think what?
&rlm;يعتقدون ماذا؟
Time, 2126 hours! Wataru Susumu taken into custody!
&rlm;الوقت، الساعة 21:26! &rlm;يقتاد "أتارو سوسومو" للحجز!
-Now taking him to interrogation room! -Roger that!
&rlm;- نأخذه الآن لغرفة التحقيق. &rlm;- علم.
Hey!
&rlm;مهلاً.
Takagi did something stupid again, didn't he?
&rlm;قام "تاكاغي" بشيء غبي مجدداً، &rlm;أليس كذلك؟
I'm sorry! There's been a mistake!
&rlm;أنا آسف! حدث خطأ!
It's a little misunderstanding! Er, I was the one who got it wrong!
&rlm;إنه سوء تفاهم صغير. &rlm;فهمت الأمر بشكل خاطىء.